Shaw, E. A. & Company Records 6615
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
E. A. Shaw & Company Records
1932-1956
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
E. A. Shaw & Company
6615
0.25 cubic feet
0.2 linear ft.
Correspondence.
Business records, 1932-1956, most from the Boston office & centering on information about ramie. Includes correspondence, all concerning ramie; some letters discuss decortication & degumming of the fibers. Also a file of information about ramie, and folders of samples of ramie twine, some of which was made in Switzerland & tested by the Plymouth Cordage Co.
11024663
Biographical / Historical
E.A. Shaw & Company, were cotton merchants and raw materials dealers with offices in Los Angeles and Boston.
Scope and Contents
Collection mostly from the Boston office and centering on information about ramie, a fiber obtained from the bark of the ramie plant. Includes correspondence, 1932-1933, 1948-1949, and 1954, all concerning ramie; some letters discuss decortication and degumming of the fibers. Also includes a file of information, 1956, about ramie; and folders of samples of ramie twine, including some made in Switzerland and tested by the Plymouth Cordage Co.
Custodial History
American Textile History Museum Collection, gift of Gordon Shaw.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
M. Clark, September 10, 2019
EAD encoding:
Marcie Farwell, October 09, 2019
Business records; Cotton trade; Plant fiber industry; Ramie; Ramie industry; Textile industry; Other natural fibers; Textile raw materials; Boston (Mass.); Los Angeles (Calif.); E. A. Shaw & Company; Plymouth Cordage Company
11024663
- Ramie Sample No. 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ramie Sample No. 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ramie Sample No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ramie Sample No. 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ramie Sample No. 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ramie Sample No. 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ramie Sample No. 7 & 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) Letters, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) -- Letter and notes with samples of Ramie, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) - Letters, with sample, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Ramie" - Ramie rope samples, made in Switzerland, tested by Plymouth Cordase Co., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Ramie", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)